<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Exercise and Out on Tim Wicks</title>
        <link>https://trwicks.github.io/categories/exercise-and-out/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Exercise and Out on Tim Wicks</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trwicks.github.io/categories/exercise-and-out/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Training #1</title>
        <link>https://trwicks.github.io/p/training-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://trwicks.github.io/p/training-1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://trwicks.github.io/p/training-1/bwdog.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Training #1" /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do nothing which is of no use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miyamoto Musashi, The Book of Five Rings (The Book of Earth)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago I suffered a few injuries - torn calf, pain in my lower back and left knee - and weakness in balance and flexibility that prevented me from training martial arts and weighlifting as usual. This period caused me to evaluate how and why I train, which led to three noticable areas that I want to change with my training into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first major change is not training too much in each session. I loosely think that I would like to improve my 75% rather than my 100%. It allows me to enjoy training on a more regular basis than pushing yourself too hard where you dislike the thought of going back to the gym the next day. Up until recently I trained with the mindset of always trying to push myself as hard as I can each workout. While this is does yield results it comes with risk of injury or burnout that may not align with what you want to achieve. By holding back a bit I feel eager to do more at the end of the session and the same feeling persists the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second change is to focus on identifying and fixing weak areas. For me this is my glutes, hip flexors, and neglected core muscle groups. I spend a lot more time trying to identify areas that need improvement and then target those areas with different exercises, seeing what helps pain and mobility. I recently worked with a great physio has helped me identify issues in my hips and knee stability, so it is great to have additional members on your fitness team to help you out. By actively monitoring weak areas and trying fixing them I find that I am putting additional tools for the workout toolbox rather than the same old workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is worth actually asking why you are training in the first place. Many people start out by formulating workout regimes to get healthy or to look better. These are great high level goals but it worth continously listening to yourself and putting thought into refining your goals, so you have long to short term goals that allow you to grow in a desired direction. The ability to learn and grow as a person through exercise and martial arts is really important to me and at some stage I would like to teach otherwise what I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on fixing weakness would be my mantra these days. My big desire is to be training long into the future, not winning crossfit competitions, so it worth putting some thought into areas that need a bit of thought and adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
